Brian Shanken

4252 Shadow Garden Drive | Hahira, GA 31632 (229) 221-0142 | bcshanken@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Professional analyst with more than seven years of experience of data and process analysis, with two years of experience developing marketing web based resources. Currently pursing education from Georgia Tech to enhance my skills as a Full Stack Web Developer. My proficiencies and skills include:

PardotSalesforceCSSHTMLNode.js

➢ Google Analytics
➢ JavaScript & ¡Query
➢ Microsoft Office

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology, Georgia Tech Coding Boot Camp

February 2021

Full Stack Web Development

Atlanta, GA

Valdosta State University, Bachelor of Science

Major in Physics, Minor in Mathematics

May 2013 Valdosta. GA

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cleaver-Brooks, Inc.

Thomasville, GA

Marketing Operations

Apr. 2017 – Present

- Maintain a data base of 20,000 prospects—consisting of developing lists based on interest, title, and industry
- Create custom engagement programs comprised of landing pages with forms, HTML emails, and integration with Salesforce lead owners
- Develop prospects into leads and distribute to multiple lead queues for sales follow-ups
- Generate reports for marketing ads, emails, and engagement programs
- Monitor and report on trends for multiple corporate websites using Google Analytics
- Compile data to develop market place insight for diverse locations and products
- Assist in SEO and AdWords programs
- Produce reports for executive team used for mapping out financial plans and guiding corporate projects

Data Software Services Valdosta, GA

Data Analyst

Jun. 2013 – Mar. 2017

- Analyzed work performance of Customer Service Representatives of the call center
- Performed statistical trend analyses for maximizing performance efficiency
- Created cost analyses of company promotions
- Presented technical findings and meaningful business insights to senior management for use in business decision making
- Analyzed and modified admin and managerial process to save time and improve accuracy. One process was improved to cut time from 4 working days to 3 hours.
- Entered high volumes of data and created into interactive statistical presentations for managers using Microsoft Excel
- Developed and maintained accurate time records to submit to payroll

Valdosta State University, Student Success Center

Valdosta, GA

Supplemental Instructor

Jan. 2012 - May. 2013

- Held review sessions for large quantities of students on various learning levels
- Assisted students in learning the material
- Maintained availability for one-on-one office appointments

Peer Tutor

Jan. 2010 - Dec. 2012

- Assisted students in reviewing and studying for over twenty mathematics and physics courses
- Lead over 3,000 appointments
- Helped students prepare for standardized testing, including college entrance exams

Front Desk Worker

Aug. 2011 – May 2012

- Received phone calls from prospective tutees and schedule appointments with appropriate tutors
- Filed paperwork and maintained the organization system

Valdosta State University, Office of Housing and Residence Life

Valdosta, GA

Resident Assistant

Aug. 2009 – May 2010

- Worked as a front desk worker providing front-line customer service to around 500 residents, their parents and guests, and other departmental staff
- Developed an inclusive community among residents, maximizing positive resident interactions
- Mediated and provided conflict resolution in a professional and timely manner
- Managed administrative duties including incident reports, maintenance requests, room transfers, monthly inspections, and implementation of various hall programs
- Assisted with audits of room keys, physical inventories of rooms, and residents living in each room
- Responded appropriately to various emergency situations

VOLUNTEER

Volunteered in Costa Rica on a five week program with International Student Volunteers, helping lay the foundations for a water tank, dig a drainage system for sewage, and pave roads in the developing community in the town of San Cristobal Norte.

As an Emerging Leader, hosted a conference aimed at building leadership development skills for members of the community.

ACTIVITIES

Society of Physics Students

Member (2008-2013)

VSU Ambassadors

President (2009-2013)

➤ Gay-Straight Alliance

Treasurer (2009-2011)

Emerging Leaders Program

Member/Leader (2008-2013)

PUBLICATIONS

D. J. Drake, J. W. R. Schroeder, B. C. Shanken, G. G. Howes, F. Skiff, C. A. Kletzing, T. A. Carter, and S. Dorfman, 2014. *Analysis of Magnetic Fields in Inertial Alfvén Wave Collisions*. Published by <u>IEEE</u> Transactions on Plasma Science (Volume 42, Issue: 10).